RG 004:052, Farmington Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Farmington Probate Court records
1769-1987
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Farmington District)
41.25 cubic feet
Record books, None; Probate files, 1769-1987.
RG004_052
1911-004, 2012-014, T003288, T003289
Historical Note
Farmington, Hartford County, Town settled 1640, established in December 1645
The Farmington Probate District was constituted January 1769 from the Hartford Probate District. In addition to processing probate matters for the municipality of Farmington, it also did so for the following municipalities at various times: Avon, May 1830 - May 1844; Berlin, May 1785 - June 1, 1824; Bristol, May 1785 - June 3, 1830; Burlington, May 1806 - June 2, 1834; New Hartford, January 1769 - October 1808; Plainville, May 1869 - May 1909; October 1779 - May 23, 1825. The Farmington Probate District merged with the Burlington Probate District on January 5, 2011 to create the Farmington and Burlington Probate District which serves the municipalities of Burlington and Farmington.
Town of Farmington, Probate District chronology:
1640 - May 1666, Hartford Colonial Jurisdiction
May 1666 - January 1769, Hartford County Court & District
January 1769 - January 4, 2011, Farmington District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Farmington and Burlington District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, None. Contact the probate court to access original record books. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1769-1987. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Arrangement
Probate Files are arranged by accession. Each accession is arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1911-004 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2012-014.
Probate Files: There is no index for the probate files in Accessions T003288 and T003289.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Avon; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Berlin; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Bristol; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Burlington; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Farmington; Probate records -- Connecticut -- New Hartford; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Plainville; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Southington
Places:
Avon (Conn.); Berlin (Conn.); Bristol (Conn.); Burlington (Conn.); Farmington (Conn.); Newe Hartford (Conn.); Plainville (Conn.); Southington (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1987 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-17, 20-22, 26, 28, 30-31, 1767-1926; probate files 1769-1908 (Accession 1911-004); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1911-004 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): November 13, 1911 (1769-1878); October 22, 1935 (1769-1908). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The probate files in accession 2012-014 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 18, 2012.
It is not known when the probate files in accessions T003288 and T003289 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
Container List
- Probate files, 1769-1908; 17 cubic feet; 1911-004
  - Ackley - Belden, J. (Drawer 1)
  - Belden, K. - Butcher (Drawer 2)
  - Butler - Cook, J. (Drawer 3)
  - Cook, K. - Curtis, L. (Drawer 4)
  - Curtis, M. - Freeman, J. (Drawer 5)
  - Freeman, K. - Griswold, J. (Drawer 6)
  - Griswold, K. - Hearne (Drawer 7)
  - Heath - Ives (Drawer 8)
  - Jackson - Lewis, J. (Drawer 9)
  - Lewis, K. - Miller, G. (Drawer 10)
  - Miller, H. - Oley (Drawer 11)
  - Olmsted - Porter, R. (Drawer 12)
  - Porter, S. - Scott, D. (Drawer 13)
  - Scott, E. - Stone, J. (Drawer 14)
  - Stone, K. - Wadsworth, S. (Drawer 15)
  - Wadsworth, T. - Winchel, L. (Drawer 16)
  - Winchel, M. - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 17)
- Inventory control book, 1769-1908; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1911-004
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, circa 1908-1940; 15 cubic feet; T003288
  There is no index for this accession
  - Abaghian - Anderson, L. (Drawer 1)
  - Anderson, M. - Barnes (Drawer 2)
  - Barney - Bauer (Drawer 3)
  - Beach - Blum (Drawer 4)
  - Bombara - Broadbent (Drawer 5)
  - Brockett - Byington (Drawer 6)
  - Campbell - Calhoun (Drawer 7)
  - Chapin - Chase (Drawer 8)
  - Chidsey - Clark (Drawer 9)
  - Cleary - Corcoran (Drawer 10)
  - Coupland - Curtis (Drawer 11)
  - Dahl - Deming, E (Drawer 12)
  - ADeming, F. - Eddy (Drawer 13)
  - Edge - Flynn (Drawer 14)
  - Ford - Gallagher (Drawer 15)
  - Gamache - Goodale (Drawer 16)
  - Goodfield - Guiden (Drawer 17)
  - Hackney - Harper (Drawer 18)
  - Hart - Hepworth (Drawer 19)
  - Hester - Hird (Drawer 20)
  - Hitchcock - Hurlburt (Drawer 21)
  - Hurley - Jones (Drawer 22)
  - Jordan - Kittenbeck (Drawer 23)
  - Klauser - Lascari (Drawer 24)
  - Laurensen - Locks (Drawer 25)
  - Loomis - McKenney (Drawer 26)
  - McKissick - Miglietti (Drawer 27)
  - Mikolojcoik - Munson (Drawer 28)
  - Murdock - O'Shea (Drawer 29)
  - Palache - Pembrook (Drawer 30)
  - Pendleton - Pope (Drawer 31)
  - Porter - Quigley (Drawer 32)
  - Rafferty - Roach (Drawer 33)
  - Robbins - Roarke, D. (Drawer 34)
  - Rourke, E. - Sanford, C. (Drawer 35)
  - Sanford, D. - Selden (Drawer 36)
  - Shanley - Smith, M. (Drawer 37)
  - Smith, N. - Smith, Z. (Drawer 38)
  - Soby - Strong, Theodore P. (Drawer 39)
  - Strong, Theodore, P. - Tharau (Drawer 40)
  - Thayer - Thomson (Drawer 41)
  - Thompson - Wadsworth (Drawer 42)
  - Wall - White (Drawer 43)
  - Whitmore - Woodford, D. (Drawer 44)
  - Woodford, E. - Zamniska; Miscellaneous (Drawer 45)
- Probate files, circa 1940-1948; 5.25 cubic feet; T003289
  - Abaghian - Betz (Drawer 1)
  - Bidwell - Bower (Drawer 2)
  - Broadbent - Chauvy (Drawer 3)
  - AChurchill - Cushman (Drawer 4)
  - Davis - Gresh (Drawer 5)
  - Grocki - Hawley (Drawer 6)
  - Hayden - Horton (Drawer 7)
  - Hotchkiss - Lanson (Drawer 8)
  - Lawler -Morgan (Drawer 9)
  - Lawler -Morgan (Drawer 10)
  - Omallao - Riddle, I. (Drawer 11)
  - Riddle, J. - Skinner (Drawer 12)
  - Skoglund - Strong, S. (Drawer 13)
  - Strong, T. - Vibert, Robert K. (Drawer 14)
  - Vibert, Robert K. - Wells. (Drawer 15)
  - Whaples - Zimmerman; Miscellaneous (Drawer 16)
- Probate files, 1870-1987; 4 cubic feet; 2012-014
  - Wills: A-H (Box 1)
  - Wills: I-R (Box 2)
  - Wills: S-Z (Box 3)
  - Probate files (Box 4)